Leonard Carmichael Papers ca.1917-1973 Mss.B.C212
American Philosophical Society
- Leonard Carmichael Papers, ca. 1917-1973 (Box 1)
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. Alan Maxwell for Arthur Lecture, Radio Waves from the Sun -, 15 Oct. 1959.
  - Speech: Introduction of Board of Judges - 16th Annual Science Talent Search., 1957 March 11
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. C.E. Kenneth Mees - Arthur Lecture - U.S. National Museum -, 21 May 1953
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. Donald H. Menzel, Arthur Lecturer, 26 April 1956
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. Erik Sjoqvist for 8th Annual Joint Lecture of Smithsonian Institution and Archaeological Institute of America -, 24 Jan. 1961
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. Erim, 19 Feb. 1973
  - Speech: Introduction of George E. Mylonas..., 1957 Feb. 6
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. George E. Mylonas Archaeological Institute of America Speech, 25 Feb. 1960
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. George Schaller, 4-5 Feb. 1973
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. Henry T. Rowell, Archaeological Institute - Smithsonian -, 28 Jan. 1954
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. Homer A. Thompson - National Museum -, 2 Dec. 1958
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. J.P. Guildford - D. C. Psychological Ass'n., 26 April 1956
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. John W. Evans - Arthur Lecture - U.S. National Museum -, 27 May 1954
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. Leo Goldberg - Twenty-Fifth James Arthur Lecture -, 23 Oct. 1958
  - Speech: Introduction of Laurence K. Marshall, 9 Feb. 1956
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. Louis S.B. Leakey, NAS -, 28 Feb. 1961
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. Louis S.B. Leakey - National Geographic Society -, 24 Feb. 1961
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. Louis S.B. Leakey at the National Geographic Society -, 22 March 1963
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. Rodney S. Young - Archaeological Institute of America - Speaker -, 27 Feb. 1958
  - Speech: Introduction of Dr. Sumner McKnight Crosby - Archeological Institute of America Smithsonian Lecture: "Excavations in the Abbey Church of St. Denis -" Freer Gallery of Art., 4 Feb. 1955
  - Speech: Introduction of James H. Doolittle Lecture -, 28 Sept. 1961
  - Speech: Introduction of George D. Beck -- Newcomen Dinner, 21 Jan. 1966
  - Speech: Introduction of James H. Doolittle Lecture, 28 Sept. 1961
  - Speech: Introduction of Millar Burrows - Joint Meeting of Archeological Institute of America and Smithsonian Inst., 29 Feb. 1956
  - Speech: Introduction of Mr. Grover Loening., 18 May 1959
  - Speech: Introduction of Mrs. Margaret Brown Klapthor, 1957 March 20
  - Speech: Introduction of Nicholas B. Clinch, 30-31 March 1967
  - Speech: Introduction of Sen. J.W. Fulbright - Opening of Exhibition "Fulbright Painters and Designers -, 28 Feb. 1959.
  - Speech: Introduction of Senator Saltonstall and Remarks at Tuft's Dinner - Washington -, 25 Feb. 1958
  - Speech: Introduction of Sir Roger Makins - Smithsonian, 1953
  - Speech: Introduction of Sister Mary Inez Hilger, 19-20 Jan. 1967
  - Speech: Introduction of Speakers - Symposium on Art and Secondary Education - Sponsored by St. Albans., 25 May 1959
  - Speech: Introduction of the Craighead Lectures, 16-17 Dec. 1965
  - Speech: Introduction of the German Ambassador - Opening of the Carl Bodmer Exhibition - Natural History Building., 6 Jan. 1955
  - Speech: Introduction of the German Ambassador - Presentation of the German Statue "Laboring Youth" to American People - Nat. Hist. Bldg., 25 Jan. 1955
  - Speech: Introduction of the Norwegian Ambassador at the Opening of "Norwegian Tapestries" Exhibit., 12 Dec. 1959
  - Speech: Introduction of the Wheatcrofts, 9-10 Dec. 1971
  - Speech: Introduction of Walter Starck, 16-17 Feb. 1967
  - Speech: Introduction of William Frank Uhl, 1 Nov. 1951
  - Speech: Introductory Address at Meeting of PORD Smithsonian Institution -, 1 April 1954
  - Speech: Introductory Remarks at the Discussion Session on Research - Conference on Mental Health -, 25 Oct. 1953
  - Speech: Introductory Remarks at the National Geographic Society., 21 Feb. 1958
  - Speech: Is Reading Obsolete - The Men's Club of St. John's. St. John's Parish House, 15 Nov. 1955
  - Speech: Is Reading Old Fashioned?, 29 Oct. 1950
  - Speech: Is there a Counterrevolution in Education - Phi Beta Kappa Lecture - Vanderbilt Univ. - Nashville, Tenn., 14 April 1959
  - Speech: Is There a Counterrevolution in Education? Wellesley Club of Washington, 13 April 1954
  - Speech: Is There a Counterrevolution in Education? Wellesley College Alumnae Council - Wellesley, Mass., 11 Feb. 1955
  - Speech: James Smithson's Dream - The Twentieth Century Club of Washington., 1 Dec. 1955
  - Speech: James Smithson's Idea, 12 March 1957
  - Speech: James Smithson's Idea - Literary Society of Washington, 26 March 1955
  - Speech: James Smithson's Idea - Sulgrave Club, 12 March 1957
  - Speech: James Smithson's Idea., 1957 March 12
    - Huntington, Frances
    - Chase, Mrs. G. Howard
  - Speech: James Smithson's Idea -, 1957 April 26
    - Eisenhart, Luther Phaler
  - Speech: Jamestown Day Speech - Never Given, 15 May 1966
  - Speech: James Smithson's Idea (Materials)
  - Speech: Joke Materials
  - Speech: Joseph Henry and his Smithsonian Institution
  - Speech: Joseph Henry and the Early History of the Smithsonian - Manuscript Society, 20 Sept. 1963
  - Speech: Joseph Henry and the National Academy of Sciences -, 25 April 1967
  - Speech: Joseph Henry and the Smithsonian Institution - The Newcomen Society Honoring the Smithsonian -, 23 March 1956
  - Speech: Justification for Planning the Museum of History and Technology - Smithsonian Institution - Hearings, House Appropriations Comm. -, 30 June 1955
  - Speech: Langfeld Memorial Lectures. Princeton University, 1967
  - Speech: Latin American Hall Opening - Smithsonian Institution -, 14 April 1954
  - Speech: A Layman Looks at the Christian Faith Today - St. John's Church -, 7 Dec. 1966
  - Speech: The Layman's View of Dental Education Mass. Dental Society -, 22 April 1940
  - Speech: Laziness and the Scholarly Life
  - Speech: Laziness and the Scholarly Life - Brown Univ. Graduate Convocation -, 30 May 1953
  - Speech: Laziness and the Scholarly Life - Brown Univ. Graduate Convocation -, 30 May 1953
  - Speech: Laziness and the Scholarly Life - Georgetown Phi Beta Kappa Address, 28 April 1966
  - Speech: Learing - "X" Club, Also Delivered Phi Delta Kappa, Harvard -, 1 Dec. 1937. 15 Feb. 1939
  - Speech: Lecture on Elementary Psychology, 16 Jan. 1947
  - Speech: Lecture Series Notes Given at AAUP Meetings - Guggenheim Hall -, June-July, 1940
  - Speech: Leonard Carmichael Society Address -, 24 May 1960
  - Speech: Let us Look at Horatio Alger Again - Tulane Univ. Commencement Address - New Orleans -, 2 June 1958
  - Speech: Liberalism can be Heroic Too - Baccalaureate Address -, 8 June 1947
  - Speech: The Machine, Servant or Master? Boston College Commencement, 13 June 1951
  - Speech: Machines and Human Freedom. Graduation Speech at Mount Vernon -, June 1959
  - Speech: Machines: Are They Servants or Master Lowell Technological Institute Commencement Address, 13 June 1955
  - Speech: The Making of the Modern Mind -- The Emergence of Mind in the Animal Series and in the Growing Individual. Rockwell Lecture Rice Institute, Houston, Texas, 1 and 2 March 1955
  - Speech: The Making of the Modern Mind, Lecture The Emergence of Mind in the Animal Series - Rockwell Lectures - Rice Institute, Houston Texas, 1 March 1955
  - Speech: The Making of the Modern Mind, Lecture The Emergence of Mind in the Growing Individual - Rockwell Lectures - Rice Institute Houston, Texas, 2 March 1955
  - Speech: Man and Society in War and Peace., 17 May 1942.
  - Speech: Man and Society in War and Peace., 21 Sept. 1943
  - Speech: Man and the Machine in the Atomic Age.
  - Speech: Man, Machines and Freedom - Mudd College Commencement Address, 6 June 1960
  - Speech: Margaret Floy Washburn Memorial Address -, 14 April 1940
  - Speech: Marjorie Merriweather Post, an Appreciation., 4 Nov. 1966
  - Speech: Mary Baldwin College, 2 Oct. 1970
    - Williams, Craven E
    - Kelly, William W
  - Speech: Mathematics and the Smithsonian Institution - Nat'l Council of Teachers of Math -, 9 April 1953
  - Speech: Men, Machines and Freedom - Univ. of Bridgeport, Commencement Address -, 2 June 1957
  - Speech: Man, Mind, and the Machine - Dickinson College - Commencement Address, 12 June 1955
  - Speech: Manpower and Human Talents, 2 March 1953
  - Speech: Manpower and Human Talents - Awards Banquet - Twelfth Annual Science Talent Search -, 2 March 1953
  - Speech: Manpower Mobilization and the College, 23 Sept. 1942
  - Speech: Meaning and Value of A Liberal Education - Delivered: Univ. of Rochester: College for Men and the College for Women, Academic Honors Day - Tufts -, Sept. 1936, and Sept. 1937. 19 Sept. 1938
  - Speech: Meaning and Value of a Liberal Education - Entering Class - and Excerpts Used over WIXAL, 22 Sept. 1938 - 15 Dec. 1938
  - Speech: Medical Research and the Conquest of Disease - New England Diabetes Ass'n - Horticultural Hall -, 13 Nov. 1950
  - Speech: Medicine and Dentistry in a World at War., 31 March. 1943
  - Speech: Memorial Address on James Smithson, At Bicentennial of James Smithson., Sept. 1965
  - Speech: Memorial for Herbert V. Neal - Goddard Chapel - Tufts Univ. -, 21 April 1940
  - Speech: Mental Health Progress in Mass. in Recent Years, Dec. 1951
  - Speech: Miscellaneous Speeches, Etc.
    - Yakovlev, Paul I
    - Halloran, Roy D
    - Lemmon, Walter S
    - Ryerson, Louise F
    - Morton, J W
    - Shea, Marjorie L
    - Davis, Helen E
    - Lanier, Lyle H
    - Pillsbury, Walter B
  - Speech: Mobilization and Training of Scientific and Specialized Manpower for the War Effort, 22 July 1942
  - Speech: Mobilization Plans and the College Student - Thayer Academy, Braintree, Mass., 30 Nov. 1950
  - Speech: Mobilization Plans and the College Student, 1951
  - Speech: Mobilizing the Nation's Expert Brains - Broadcast over WEEI, Boston., 28 Nov. 1940
  - Speech: Modern Psychology and the Understanding of the Individual and the Family, 21 Feb. 1945
  - Speech: Modern Technique for the Measurement of Visually-Released Reactions in Mammals - Rochester Chapter of Optical Society of America, 4 May 1937
  - Speech: A Moment with... NBC TV Program, 26 Dec. 1961
  - Speech: My Most Important Childhood Lesson, 1960 Nov. 5
  - Speech: National Geographic Society, 1962 Dec. 12
  - Speech: National Roster and Wartime Engineering Education, 28 June 1942
  - Speech: The Nation's Professional Manpower Resources., 7 Feb. 1945
  - Speech: Neo-Patriotism-Convocation, 2 Oct. 1940
  - Speech: New England Looks at Itself -, 7 Dec. 1951
  - Speech: The New First Ladies Hall of The Smithsonian Inst. - Arts and Industries Bldg. -, 24 May 1955
  - Speech: New Opportunities for Democracy in Education., 3 June 1944
  - Speech: New Plans for Postwar College Education, 8 Nov. 1944
  - Speech: New Role of the Museum in American Life, 13 June 1962
  - Speech: Newcomen Dinner, 21 Nov. 1963
  - Speech: Newcomen Society Dinner, 19 Nov. 1964
  - Speech: Newcomen Dinner - in honor of Perpetual Building Ass'n., 19 Nov. 1965
    - Sherwood, J Robert
    - Johnston, S Paul
    - Morrison, Eric Hall
    - Baltz, Edward C
    - Penrose, Charles, Jr.
  - Speech: Newcomen Society Dinner, 24 March 1961
  - Speech: Newcomen Society - Mayflower Hotel, 4 Nov. 1966
  - Speech: Notes on Psychology Lecture., 3 Oct. 1947
  - Speech: Notes on the Development of the National Portrait Gallery, 21 Oct. 1963
  - Speech: Nursing in a World at War., 11 Feb. 1942
  - Speech: Nursing in a World at War., 26 April 1944
  - Speech: Observation on Education and on Educational and Vocational Guidance... Paris., 24-27 Oct. 1960
  - Speech: On Animal Behavior
  - Speech: On Becoming Educated., 10 June 1945
  - Speech: On Citizenship Conference on Citizenship, 8 May 1947
  - Speech: On College Trained Men and Mobilization - Matriculation Day - Tufts College, 15 Sept. 1950
  - Speech: On Democracy, 1951
  - Speech: On Education
  - Speech: On Education - Commencement - Lawrence Academy -, 7 June 1947
  - Speech: On Establishment of a National Science Foundation., 1 Dec. 1945
  - Speech: On Examinations
  - Speech: On Expecting the Wrong things from Education - Univ. of Buffalo - Commencement -, 8 June 1938
  - Speech: On Labor Relations - Chamber of Commerce Luncheon, 13 Dec. 1940
  - Speech: On Military Psychology - Ass'n. of N.R.O.T.C. Colleges Meeting Annapolis -, 1 April 1950.
  - Speech: On Nursing - Butler Hospital Commencement -, 28 May 1940.
  - Speech: On Reading - for the Ass'n of Independent Schools of Greater Washington at Mount Vernon Seminary, 20 Oct. 1959
  - Speech: On Scholarship - Academic Honors -, Nov. 1948
  - Speech: On Scholarship - Honors Day Address - Goddard Chapel - Tufts Univ., 5 Nov. 1947
  - Speech: On Teaching Democracy in Elementary Schools - Mutual Broadcasting, 6 Nov. 1951
  - Speech: On the National Geographic Society
  - Speech: On the National Register
  - Speech: On the Need for Selective Service., 1951
  - Speech: Observations on the Role of the Henry Francis DuPont Winterthur Museum in the Educational and Cultural Life of America., 1961 March.
  - Speech: On the Smithsonian and the Need for New Buildings - National Conference of Newspapers Editors. Smithsonian Institution., 28 Oct. 1954
  - Speech: On the Smithsonian, Education, and Life Mount Vernon Junior College - Alumnae Day -, 28 May 1955
  - Speech: On the Smithsonian Institution - National Society of the Colonial Dames of America, 19 Nov. 1959.
  - Speech: On the Smithsonian, to OEDPA., 15 April 1958
  - Speech: On Trip Abroad - Tufts Chapt. - AAUP -, 20 Oct. 1948
  - Speech: On Tufts' History (Notes), 21 Dec. 1947
  - Speech: Opening of Hall 11 - Smithsonian Inst., Nat. Hist. Bldg., 2 June
  - Speech: Opening of Hall of Military History, 14 June 1958
  - Speech: Opening of Marine Corps Exhibit - National Museum., 10 August, 1954.
  - Speech: Opening of Per Krohg Exhibition - National Museum -, 15 June 1954
  - Speech: Opening of Special Music Exhibit -, 31 Aug. 1961
  - Speech: Opening of the Hall of Life in the Sea, 8 Feb. 1963
  - Speech: Opening of the Hall of North American Archaeology, 24 June 1961
  - Speech: Opening Remarks at 49th Annual Meeting, Harvard Teacher's Ass'n., 16 March 1940
  - Speech: Opening Remarks - Census Exhibit Opening -, 10 March 1960
  - Speech: Opening Remarks - XVII International Congress of Psychology, 20 Aug. 1963
  - Speech: Opening Remarks of the Charles Lang Freer Medal - Freer Gallery -, 25 Feb. 1956
  - Speech: Opening Remarks to the Press at the Presentation of the Jubilee Diamond, 8 Nov. 1961
  - Speech: Our First Fifty Years as a Prelude to Greater Things., 29 March 1944
  - Speech: Our Menacing Anti-Intellectualism -, 3 June 1951
  - Speech: Panel Discussion, Conference of Superintendents of Schools and High School Principals., 15 April 1946
  - Speech: Panel Discussion Art and Secondary Education - St. Albans School (Moderator), 25 May 1959
  - Speech: The Past and Future of James Smithson's Dream - Washington Chapter, Phi Beta Kappa, 31 Jan. 1956
  - Speech: Personnel Recruitment for Women., 20 March 1942
  - Speech: Phi Beta Kappa Address at Boston Sp
  - Speech: Philosophy of Conservation. Address before the Robert E. Lee Memorial Foundation, Stratford Hall, 2 May 1965
    - Hollister, Mrs. Florence
    - Harrison, Mrs. Mary H
  - Speech: A Philosophy of Historic Preservation Annual Dinner - National Trust for Historic Preservation -, 19 Oct. 1963
  - Speech: Phylogenetic Development of Behavior Patterns
  - Speech: Phylogenetic Development of Behavior Patterns - Ass'n for Research in Nervous and Mental Disease Symposium -, 11 Dec. 1953
  - Speech: Physiological Correlates of Intelligence - Harvard Teachers Assoc., 10 March 1941
  - Speech: The Place of Psychology in the American Victory Program., 18 April 1942
  - Speech: Planning for Defense and Peace - Honors Day -, 15 Oct. 1941
  - Speech: Planning for Freedom., 9 May 1943
  - Speech: Planning for Higher Education in Periods of National Stress. Am Council on Education - Chicago, 7 May 1948
  - Speech: Play in Animals and Men in Relation to Esthetic Theory Chicago, 5 Sept. 1960
  - Speech: The Political Obligations of University Trained Veterans.
  - Speech: Pragmatic Humanism and American Higher Education., Nov. 1938
  - Speech: Presentation Ceremony - Specimen by Kloeckner-Humboldt-Deutz A.G. - Hall of Power Machinery -, 17 Sept. 1957.
  - Speech: Presentation of Inverted Air Mail Stamp - Arts and Industries Bldg., 27 May 1958.
  - Speech: Presentation of the Charles Lang Freer Medal to Prof. Ernst Kuehnel, 3 May 1960
  - Speech: Presentation of the Hope Diamond, 10 Nov. 1958
  - Speech: Presentation of the Langley Medal and Acceptance of the Atlas Missle, 28 June 1960
  - Speech: Presentation of the Vanguard Rocket - Rotunda - Arts and Industries Bldg., 26 May 1958
  - Speech: Presentation for "Plus Ultra", 20 March 1963
  - Speech: Presentation of Al Capp's Lil Abner Drawings - The Regents Room., 14 Nov. 1955
  - Speech: Presentation of Star Sapphire, 14 Oct. 1963
  - Speech: Presentation of Telstar, 10 July 1963
  - Speech: Presentation of the Gen. Thomas D. White Space Trophy for 1962, 3 June 1963
  - Speech: President's Panel, Meeting of the National Recreation Ass'n, 10 Oct. 1939
  - Speech: The Problem of Human Efficiency in Naval Tasks. Special Devices Center, Sands Point, N.Y., 20 Sept. 1947.
  - Speech: The Profession of Nursing - Rochester Hospitals Commencement - Eastman Theater -, 28 May 1937
  - Speech: Program of Observance of Brotherhood Week, 1957 Feb. 19
  - Speech: Progress Report, Annual Banquet, Tufts Medical Alumni Ass'n., 8 April 1948
  - Speech: Promote National Cultural Center at Mrs. Ralph E. Becker's., 1962 Nov. 27
  - Speech: Psychological Aspects of Marital Maladjustment (Notes) - Sociology Club -, 19 Nov. 1936.
  - Speech: Psychological Aspects of the Rehabilitation of Servicement., 27 April 1944.
  - Speech: The Psychological Background of General Education
  - Speech: Psychological Fundamentals and the Beginning Course., 2 Sept. 1951
  - Speech: Psychological Principles in the Design and Operation of Military Equipment., 15-16 Aug. 1945
  - Speech: The Psychologists
  - Speech: A Psychologist's Interest in Movies
  - Speech: Psychology
  - Speech: Psychology and American Democracy - Symposium with Association of Scientific Workers -, 29 Dec. 1940
  - Speech: Psychology and Behavior before Birth -, 2 Oct. 1950
  - Speech: Psychology and Manpower Utilization., 3 Sept. 1952
  - Speech: Psychology and the Study of Genius - Literary Society -, 11 March 1961
  - Speech: Psychology and Universal Military Training, Sept. 1951
  - Speech: Psychology and War., 16 Jan. 1942
  - Speech: Psychology and War., 23 July 1943
  - Speech: Psychology and War., 19 Jan. 1945. 21 July 1944
  - Speech: Psychology and the War., 26 April 1943
  - Speech: Psychology Applied to Modern Warfare., 1942
  - Speech: [Psychology as a "New Science"]
  - Speech: Psychology and Nursing - Annual Convention of Mass. State Nurses Ass'n, Nass. League of Nursing Education, and Mass. Organization for Public Health Nursing -, 1 Nov. 1939
  - Speech: Psychology and Prenatal Behavior - Examiner Club -, 2 Oct. 1950
  - Speech: Psychology and the Study of Genius - Literary Society -, 11 March 1961
  - Speech: Psychology of Genius - Delivered: Fortnightly Club - Rochester - Tau Beta Pi Initiation Banquet - Boston Chapter OBK - Tufts College - Honors Day Convocation, R.I. State College - Phi Beta Kappa - Wilson College - Chambersurg, Pa., 1937 and 1939 30 March 1937; 5 April 1939; 24 May 1933; 9 Oct. 1933; 17 April 1956.
  - Speech: Psychology of Teaching Psychology - Am. Psyc. Ass'n. -, 6 Sept. 1955.
  - Speech: Psychology, the Machine, and Society - Arthur Dehon Little Memorial Lecture at MIT -, 17 Nov. 1953
  - Speech: Psychology - Today and Tomorrow., 1936 April
  - Speech: The Radcliffe Club, 1957 Feb. 7
  - Speech: Reading and Education: A Reevaluation., 8 Dec. 1959
  - Speech: Reading and Life., 19 Jan. 1950
  - Speech: Reading and Life., 5 Feb. 1950
  - Speech: Reading and Life., 3 March 1950
  - Speech: Reading and Life - Honors Day - Governor Dummer Academy -, 14 May 1948
  - Speech: Reading and Life - James Bowdoin Day --, 23 Oct. 1946
  - Speech: Reading and Human Nature, 10 May 1956; 8 Dec. 1959.
  - Speech: Reading and Human Nature - Honors Day Address, Oberlin College -, 10 May 1956
  - Speech: Reading and the Life of the Mind - Honors Convocation - Michigan State Normal College. Ypsilanti, Mich., 4 May 1955
  - Speech: Reading and Scholarship, 16 April 1961
  - Speech: Reading and Scholarship - Phi Beta Kappa Address. Tulane Univ., 16 April 1961
  - Speech: Reading and Scholarship. Rider College, N.J., 29 April 1965
    - Pratt, Carroll C
  - Speech: Reading and Scholarship - Skidmore College -, 1 Nov. 1961
  - Speech: Reading and Visual Fatigue
  - Speech: Reading and Visual Fatigue. A.P.S., Nov. 20, 1947
  - Speech: Reading and Visual Fatigue - 52nd Annual Congress of the American Optometric Ass'n., 26 June 1949
  - Speech: Reading and Visual Fatigue - Maryland Chapt. of the Sigma Xi - Univ. of Maryland, 19 April 1955
  - Speech: Reading and Visual Fatigue - Sigma Xi Initiation - Catholic Univ. -, 6 May 1957
  - Speech: Reading and Visual Fatigue - Sigma Xi Univ. of Virginia, 5 May 1953
  - Speech: Reading and Visual Fatigue - Univ. of Maryland - Chapter Society of the Sigma Xi -, 19 April 1955.
  - Speech: Recent Planning Activities for Military Psychology in Dept. of Defense. Division 19 Symposium. Hotel Statler -, 2 Sept. 1958.
  - Speech: Recorded Speech for Broadcast on Smithsonian with Miss Markel, 27 March 1961.
  - Speech: a "Red Cross" for Cultural Property. Amherst College Alumni day., 12 June 1954.
  - Speech: Relation of Tufts and the Medical Center - The Boston Dispensary -, 29 March 1940.
  - Speech: Relationship between Medical and Premedical Studies, 24 Jan. 1944.
  - Speech: Relationship of the Federal Government to Education, 4 Dec. 1942.
  - Speech: Remarks accepting Beech Aircraft from Red Devil Tool G. - National Airport -, 14 Sept. 1960
  - Speech: Remarks at Academic Honors Day, 5 Nov. 1942.
  - Speech: Remarks at Acceptance of Jupiter C Rocket with Explorer I Satelitte -, 31 Jan. 1959.
  - Speech: Remarks at Alumni Luncheon -, 17 June 1939
  - Speech: Remarks at Tau Beta Pi Initiation., 24 Nov. 1942.
  - Speech: Remarks at the "Able-Baker" Space Equipment Presentation Ceremony, 17 Nov. 1960
  - Speech: Remarks at the Acceptance of Platforming and Polymerization Models from Universal Oil Products -, 2 Feb. 1961.
  - Speech: Remarks at the Annual Science Service Awards Banquet, 2 March 1959.
  - Speech: Remarks at the Ceremony at National Zoological Park for Okapis - Belgian Congo -, 28 Nov. 1956.
  - Speech: Remarks at the Christmas Party, 1963
  - Speech: Remarks at the Commemorative Ceremony of the Whittle Wix Gas Turbine Aero-Engine.., 15 May 1962.
  - Speech: Remarks at Dedication of British Flag - Smithson Alcove -, 24 June 1953
  - Speech: Remarks at the Dedication of the Service Flag., 7 Dec. 1942.
  - Speech: Remarks at the Gift of Mexican Painting, 10 Aug. 1960.
  - Speech: Remarks at the Junior League Training Course Meeting -, 11 Nov. 1961.
  - Speech: Remarks at the Massachusetts Schoolmasters' Club Luncheon., 10 April 1943.
  - Speech: Remarks at the Medical and Dental Dedication., 9 April 1951.
  - Speech: Remarks at the Medical School Faculty Dinner, 1 Feb. 1939.
  - Speech: Remarks at the Meeting of the Tufts Chapter of the AAUP., 20 Nov. 1952.
  - Speech: Remarks at the NATO Symposium on Psychology - Paris, 1960.
  - Speech: Remarks at the Newcomen Dinner, 12 Jan. 1962.
  - Speech: Remarks at the Newcomen Dinner, 26 Oct. 1962.